geogebra.org 2019-12-30

# Privacy – GeoGebra

Last updated: May 12, 2018

Welcome to the website and online services (the "Website") of GeoGebra!

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes the information we gather from you, how we use that information, and what we do to protect it. By using the Website (whether or not you are a registered user), you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this policy.  
Children, typically students in K-12 education, are given additional and special privacy assurances, described in the section 'Our Commitment to Children's Privacy'.  
Your use of the Website and any personal information you provide on the Website are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and GeoGebra's Terms of Service. Any capitalized terms used but not defined herein shall have the meaning set forth in the Terms of Service.  
The collection, administration and use of personal details by GeoGebra complies with applicable data protection laws (General Data Protection Regulation, GDPR) by ensuring that each user is able to decide herself, which personal details shall be made accessible to other users.  
Please take a moment to read everything carefully. In case of further questions please do not hesitate to contact us at [office@geogebra.org](mailto:office@geogebra.org).

## Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. If GeoGebra learns that personally identifiable information of children has been collected on the Website without parental consent, then GeoGebra will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or legal guardian and discover that your child has a registered account with the Website without your consent, then you may alert GeoGebra at [office@geogebra.org](mailto:office@geogebra.org) and request that GeoGebra delete that child's personal information from its systems.  
In particular, we never share the personal information of any user with third parties.  
It's important to remember that you do not need to register or sign in to the Website in order to use the GeoGebra software and access millions of GeoGebra resources.

## The Information GeoGebra Collects

User-provided Information: When you register for, browse and use the Website, you may provide to GeoGebra what is generally called "personally identifiable information". Certain information has to be given by a user in order to register for a GeoGebra Account, such as:

  * A unique username
  * E-mail address

Certain information is optional after registration and can also be added or deleted later on by the user, such as:

  * Your full name
  * Whether you are a Teacher or a Student
  * Gender
  * Year of Birth
  * Your geographical location
  * URL of further/private website
  * A personal text about yourself
  * Profile picture

After Registration different types of data are collected by GeoGebra, such as:

  * When you follow other users on our website
  * When you join a group on our website

If you decide to register through or otherwise grant access to a third party social networking or integrated service that we may make available ("Integrated Service"), such as Microsoft, Facebook, or Google, GeoGebra may also collect any such "personally identifiable information" that you have provided to the Integrated Service from the account you have with the Integrated Service. You may revoke GeoGebra's access to your account on the Integrated Service at any time by updating the appropriate settings in the account preferences of the respective Integrated Service. You should check your privacy settings on each Integrated Service to understand and change the information sent to us through each Integrated Service. Please review each Integrated Service's terms of use and privacy policies carefully before using their services and connecting to our Website. From time to time, GeoGebra may also ask you optionally to provide other information. If you choose to provide such information, during registration or otherwise, you are giving GeoGebra the permission to use and store it consistent with this policy. Therefore, please understand that if you choose to register an account and sign in to the Website, you are not anonymous to us.

Information from other Users: We may make available certain features in the Website that allow other Users of the Website to provide us information that may include personally identifiable information that you provided when registering an account. For example, we may permit a Teacher to register a service for you on your behalf in which the Teacher pre-populates certain teaching/instructional features (in GeoGebra Groups for example) with information about you.

"Cookies" Information: When you visit the Website, whether or not you are a registered user, we may send one or more cookies - small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer. Cookies are used by GeoGebra to provide a more user-friendly, effective and secure service. Cookies remember information about your activities on a website. GeoGebra may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Website. Persistent cookies can be removed. Please review your web browser "Help" file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. However, without cookies you will not have access to certain services and features on the Website.

Google Analytics: This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. We process your data on the basis of our prevailing legitimate interest to cost-efficiently generate easy to use website access statistics (Article 6(1)(f) General Data Protection Regulation). The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address and the URLs of the accessed pages) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. We do not store any of your personal data collected in connection with Google Analytics. This website uses an IP anonymization feature provided by Google Analytics. Your IP address will therefore be truncated/anonymized by Google as soon as it receives it. On our behalf, Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to us. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of your data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. Further information concerning Google’s terms of use and privacy statement can be found at <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html>.

Plugins and Widgets for Social Media: GeoGebra includes social media plugins of following social networks:

  * Facebook, which is operated by Facebook.Inc, 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA
  * Twitter, offered by Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA
  * Google +, provided by Google Inc., located at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA
  * YouTube, provided by YouTube LLC, located at 901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA.
  * OpenStreetMap, an open community, licensed under the Open Data Commons Open Database License (ODbL) by the OpenStreetMap Foundation (OSMF), located at 132 Maney Hill Road, Sutton Coldfield, West Midlands, B72 1JU, UK

For data protection/privacy reasons the mentioned plugins are deactivated by default and must be explicitly activated by you during your use hereof. Before activating these plugins please note the following information regarding the mentioned providers:

Such plugins can recognize a user’s IP address and the page visited on our website and, possibly, store cookies, so that the services offered by GeoGebra work properly. Social media plugins and widgets are hosted either by third party providers or directly by us. Your interactions with these plugins are subject to this privacy policy or the privacy policy of any third party that offers such feature. GeoGebra is not responsible for the use of, or guidelines regarding the use of, personal data by third party providers. Users may recognize the respective plugins, e.g., by the respective logo or other respective characteristic typical for the respective social media-platform on our pages. If a user interacts with the plugins, e. g. by clicking on the Facebook "Like-Button" or entering a comment, while being logged in to such user's Social Media-account on Facebook, Google+, or Twitter, a user links the contents of the GeoGebra pages to his or her respective social media-profile. Thereby, Facebook/Google+/Twitter can associate a user's visit of the GeoGebra page or use of GeoGebra Products with such user's social media-account. GeoGebra as the provider of the GeoGebra Products does not have any knowledge of the content of the transmitted data or its usage by Facebook, Google+, or Twitter. Users can find more information on the issue of data transmission in the privacy policy of the respective social media-platform:

  * Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>
  * Google+: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>
  * Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy>
  * YouTube: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>
  * OpenStreetMap: <https://operations.osmfoundation.org/policies/>

"Automatically Collected" Information: When you use the Website, we may automatically record certain information from your browser by using different types of technology, including standard log files, "clear gifs" or "web beacons." This "automatically collected" information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring or exit pages, click stream data, operating system and the dates and times that you visit the Website. Additionally, we may record certain information regarding your use of features that GeoGebra may make available on the Website, such as the number of resources you have published.

Third Party Web Beacons: GeoGebra doesn't permit any third party advertising in our apps or web services.

Location Information: We may collect and store information about your location if you enable your computer or mobile device to send us location information. You may be able to change the settings on your computer or mobile device to prevent it from providing us with such information.

Information from Other Sources: We may also obtain information, including personally identifiable information, from third parties and sources other than the Website such as an Integrated Service like Facebook or Google+. If we combine or associate information from other sources with personally identifiable information that we collect through the Website, we will treat the combined information as personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## The Way GeoGebra Uses Information

GeoGebra uses the information that you provide or that we collect in order to establish and enhance our relationship with you. GeoGebra generally uses the information you provide or that we collect to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the Website. We also use personal information for loss prevention and anti-fraud purposes. If you have given GeoGebra consent, we may use your personally identifiable information to provide you with information about GeoGebra's features, services and other offerings that may be of interest to you.

We may use your personal information, including date of birth, to verify identity, assist with identification of users, and to determine appropriate services. For example, we may use date of birth to determine the age of GeoGebra account holders.

GeoGebra uses all of the information that you provide or that we collect from Users to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our Users, to improve the way the Website works and looks, and to create new features and functionality.

GeoGebra may use "cookies" information to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Website; (b) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (c) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.

GeoGebra's employees, agents and contractors must have a legitimate operational reason to obtain access to the personally identifiable information you may provide to register an account on our Website.

## When GeoGebra Discloses Information

User Postings on the Website: GeoGebra enables you to share your User Postings (like GeoGebra resources or books you created on the platform, for example) with other Users of the Website. GeoGebra may also permit you to share your User Postings publicly on the Website. If your User Postings are shared with other Users, any personally identifiable information that you choose to include in, or is associated with, such User Postings will be accessible by these Users. Once you make your personally identifiable information available to others in any of these ways, it may be collected and used by the recipients without restriction. GeoGebra enables Users to share information and resources.

Social Networks: GeoGebra will disclose your personal information if you have explicitly agreed that we may do so. In particular, we will disclose personal information where you have elected to connect your account on our Website to a social network or other similar service (like Facebook or Google, for example), or have elected to have your activity on our Website published to a social network or other similar service. To control the information that you share, you should review and, if appropriate, modify your privacy settings on such services.

Required by Law: GeoGebra may also disclose User information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with national or international laws (such as copyright law) or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena, or warrant. In some cases, we may make such disclosures without first providing notice to Users.

Merger or Acquisition: In the event that GeoGebra is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

Other Purposes: GeoGebra also reserves the right to disclose User information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; protect GeoGebra from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Website; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of GeoGebra, our Users, or others.

## Your Choices

You may, of course, decline to share your personally identifiable information with GeoGebra, in which case GeoGebra will not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality found on the Website. If you register as a user of the Website, you may update, correct, or delete your profile information and preferences at any time by going to your account settings page at [http://accounts.geogebra.org](http://accounts.geogebra.org/).

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy and strength of your unique password and account information at all times.

### Deletion of User Information

In case of termination of the registered GeoGebra user’s account. All personal details provided by the user upon registration shall be deactivated. Any details made public by the user on our website will be

  * Anonymized, ie. it will be made clear that details were provided by a deleted user, or
  * Deleted in the event of cancellation within 1 day, and
  * All provided user information not required for GeoGebra’s performance of contractual obligations or compliance with statutory retention obligations shall be irrevocably deleted.

If you wish to close your account please go to [https://accounts.geogebra.org](https://accounts.geogebra.org/) and click on “Delete your account”. GeoGebra will maintain a record of deletion for 1 year after the deletion.

### Your rights in connection with your personal data

Under applicable law, you have, among others, the right (under the conditions set out in applicable law):

  * To check whether and what kind of personal data we hold about you and to request copies of such data
  * To request correction, supplementation or deletion of your personal data that is inaccurate or processed in non-compliance with applicable requirements, and
  * To request us to restrict the processing of your personal data
  * In certain circumstances, to object for legitimate reasons to the processing of your personal data or to revoke consent previously granted for the processing
  * To request data portability
  * To know the identities of third parties to which your personal data are transferred, and
  * To lodge a complaint with the competent authority.

## Accessing Services through Other Sites

You may encounter GeoGebra provides math apps and classroom resources services on websites and in apps operated by other organizations or companies. Some of these websites may be co-branded with our name or logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party websites and third party servers if you choose to use GeoGebra services through these third parties. GeoGebra's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other third parties.

## Our Commitment to Data Security

GeoGebra uses certain physical, managerial, and technical safeguards designed to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to GeoGebra, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, GeoGebra makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

If GeoGebra learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. GeoGebra may post a notice on the Website if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

## International Visitors

The Website is intended for visitors from all countries, given our worldwide community of users. If you choose to use the Website from countries with laws governing data collection and use that differ from Austrian law, then please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those regions to be held on our servers in Austria and third party server services located in other countries and by providing your personally identifiable information you consent to that transfer.

## Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change the privacy policy at our sole discretion. GeoGebra users will be informed of any such change by us posting a new privacy policy on the Website and the effective date of any change of privacy policy will be clearly marked. We will not use any personally identifiable information of yours in ways that are materially different from the ones described in this Privacy Policy without also providing notification of such practices and obtaining consent to any such different uses. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you by email and by means of a notice on our Website.

## Our Contact Information

Please address your requests or questions concerning the processing of your personal data to:

GeoGebra GmbH  
Altenbergerstraße 69  
4040 Linz  
Austria
